Guide to the James Joyce Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- SERIES V. SLOCUM & CAHOON MATERIAL (1967-1993), (3 boxes)
  - WRITINGS ABOUT JOYCE
    - Byrne, J. F. SILENT YEARS Galley Proof, 1953 (Box 36, Folder 602-03)
    - Connolly, Thomas E. JAMES JOYCE'S SCRIBBLEDEHOBBLE Galley Proof, 1961 (Box 36, Folder 604)
    - Edel, Leon THE PSYCHOLOGICAL NOVEL: 1900-1950 Galley Proof, 1955 (Box 36, Folder 605)
    - Gilbert, Stuart, ed. LETTERS OF JAMES JOYCE Galley Proof, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 606)
    - Joyce, Stanislaus RECOLLECTIONS OF JAMES JOYCE Galley Proof, 1949 (Box 36, Folder 607)
    - Manning, Mary PASSAGES FROM FINNEGANS WAKE Galley Proof, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 608)
    - PORTRAIT OF JAMES JOYCE, BBC Program Radio script, 1950 (Box 37, Folder 609)
    - Read, Forrest, Ed. POUND/JOYCE: THE LETTERS OF EZRA POUND TO JAMES JOYCE Galley Proof, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 610)
    - Simpson, Herbert [EXTRACT FROM ULYSSES ], holograph, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 611)
    - Slocum. John J. and Herbert Cahoon BIBLIOGRAPHY OF JAMES JOYCE: ILLUSTRATIONS [prints and negatives], 1955 (Box 37, Folder 612)
    - Slocum, John J. and Herbert Cahoon FIVE MORE PAGES OF JAMES JOYCE'S STEPHEN HERO: INTRODUCTION Galley Proof (Box 37, Folder 613)
- SERIES VI. MATERIAL REMOVED FROM CATALOGED PRINTED ITEMS, (1 box)
  This series contains materials which were removed from
  printed items when a group of Slocum and Cahoon was
  cataloged in 1998.
  - Letter: Frank Budgen to John J. Slocum, 1948 Sep 1 (Box 41, Folder 613a)
    Removed from: Philippe Soupault, Souvenirs de James Joyce, Charlot,
    1943
  - Notes for an index of The Egoist (Box 41, Folder 613b)
    Removed from: issues of The Egoist,
    1914-16
  - Notes for a review of Patricia Hutchins' [Patricia Greacen] James Joyce's Dublin by John J. Slocum for The New York Times Book Review, 1950 Sep (Box 41, Folder 613c)
    Also contains letters between Slocum
    and The New York Times Book Review concerning the review, 1950 Sep
    Removed from: Patricia Hutchins, James Joyce's Dublin, Grey Walls
    Press, 1950
  - Postcard: Herbert Cahoon to John J. Slocum, 1948 Apr 23 (Box 41, Folder 613)
    Removed from: Lucille Coleman, Strange Altar: poems, Press of
    James A. Decker, 1947
  - Presentation note: E. Scheuer Books to Herbert Cahoon, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 613e)
  - Receipt for purchase of book: Bumarap, 1948 Dec 23 (Box 41, Folder 613)
    Removed from: Samuel Roth, Bumarap: the Story of a Male Virgin, Arrowhead
    Books, 1947
  - Wine label: Zeltinger White Moselle Wine, 1932 (Box 41, Folder 613g)
    Removed from: Stephen Spender, Destructive Element: A Study of Modern Writers and Beliefs, Jonathan Cape,
    1935
- OVERSIZE
  Oversize material is arranged according to
  original series placement.
  - SERIES II. WRITINGS
    - WORKS BY JOYCE
      - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE: French, [1930] (Box bsd, folder 641)
      - Translation Galley proofs 7p.
    - MUSICAL SETTINGS & ADAPTATIONS
      - OUT BY DONNYCARNEY, 1910 (Box 38, Folder 614)
      - FROM DEWY DREAMS, 1924 (Box 38, Folder 615)
      - GOLDENHAIR, 1925 (Box 38, Folder 616)
      - I HEAR AN ARMY, 1927 (Box 38, Folder 617)
      - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE, 1935 (Box 38, Folder 618)
      - A FLOWER GIVEN TO MY DAUGHTER, 1942 (Box 38, Folder 619)
      - RAHOON, 1947 (Box 38, Folder 620)
      - SIX COMMENTAIRES POUR ULYSSE DE JAMES, 1948 (Box 38, Folder 621)
      - JOYCE
        F29 Thomas de Hartmann Ulysses
      - BID ADIEU, 1949 (Box 38, Folder 622)
      - 4 PIESNI, 1949 (Box 38, Folder 623)
      - TRE POEMI, 1950 (Box 38, Folder 624)
      - 4 Songs, 1926, 1927 (Box 38, Folder 625)
        Tibor Serly Sleep now; Gentle Lady
        All Day; and Silently She's Coming.
  - SERIES III. SPECIAL FILES
    - CLIPPINGS ABOUT JOYCE
      Joyce as a literary figure
      - 1924
      - 1930 (Box 38, Folder 627)
      - 1953 January-December (Box 38, Folder 628)
      - Misc. (Box 38, Folder 629)
      - GIACOMO JOYCE
        - 1968 (Box 39, Folder 630)
      - FINNEGANS WAKE
        - 1939 January-May (Box 39, Folder 631)
        - 1947 (Box 39, Folder 632)
      - A PORTRAIT OF THE ARTIST AS A YOUNG MAN
        - 1917 January-April (Box 39, Folder 633)
      - ULYSSES
        - 1922 April (Box 40, Folder 634)
        - 1933 (Box 40, Folder 635)
    - CLIPPINGS ABOUT ADAPTATIONS OF WORKS BY JOYCE:
      - ULYSSES 1924 Feb 22: Chicago Tribune review of Cyclops has a note by James Joyce (Box 40, Folder 636)
    - CLIPPINGS AND REVIEWS OF WORKS ABOUT JOYCE
      - Misc. (Box 40, Folder 637)
    - PROGRAMS & PROSPECTI ABOUT JOYCE
      - Misc. (Box 40, Folder 638)
    - PHOTOGRAPHS OF JOYCE AND HIS FAMILY:
      - Girl Reading Ulysses (Box 40, Folder 639)
  - SERIES IV. SLOCUM AND CAHOON MATERIAL (1931-1966)
    - EXHIBITIONS OF SLOCUM COLLECTION MATERIAL
      - Institute of Contemporary Arts (London, 1950) Accompanied by photographs of the exhibition. (Box 40, Folder 640)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.21; (1 box)
  Restricted Fragile, contains fragile originals. The
  material may only be seen with the permission of the
  curator.
  - Box 23, folder 448 (Box cs, Folder 642)
  - Box 23, folder 449 (Box cs, Folder 643)